cymbalta.com 2016-10-19

# Privacy

**Privacy at Eli Lilly and Company**

Eli Lilly and Company ("Lilly") has established a comprehensive privacy program, including a global privacy office and a chief privacy officer, designed to help us respect and protect your privacy rights. This statement includes the Social Security Number Protection Policy and the Website Privacy Statement.

**CONSENT TO PROCESSING IN THE UNITED STATES AND ELSEWHERE.** This site is owned and operated by Lilly in the United States, but the Personal Information you provide may be accessible to our affiliates, vendors and suppliers in other countries. If you are visiting this site from a country other than the United States, your Personal Information collected on this site will be transferred outside of your country. The level of legal protection for Personal Information is not the same in all countries and the laws may be more protective in your country than in countries where we process your information; however, we will take reasonable efforts and security measures as described in this Privacy Statement in an effort to keep your information secure. By using this site, you consent to the collection, storage, and processing of your Personal Information in the United States and in any country to which we may transfer your information in the course of our business operations. In addition to its internal global privacy policies, Lilly follows and (provided the Safe Harbors are valid as determined by the relevant EU, Swiss, and US authorities) complies with the privacy and data protection principles set forth in the EU – US and Swiss – US Safe Harbors for the protection of EU and Swiss personal information.

**Social Security Number Protection Policy**

Eli Lilly and Company collects Social Security numbers and other sensitive personal information in the ordinary course of its business. Lilly has implemented reasonable technical, physical and administrative safeguards to help protect the Social Security numbers and other sensitive personal information from unlawful use and unauthorized disclosure. All Lilly workers are required to follow these established procedures, both online and offline. In particular:

  * Access to Social Security numbers is limited to those workers and service providers who have a need to access the information to perform tasks for Lilly. Social Security numbers are only disclosed to third parties in accordance with Lilly’s established privacy policy.
  * We will only disclose Social Security numbers (i) with those service providers, auditors, advisors, and/or successors in interest who are legally or contractually obligated to protect them, or (ii) as required or permitted by law.

Lilly Website Privacy Statement

Lilly respects the privacy of visitors to its websites, as a result, we have developed this website privacy statement. This Privacy Statement, with the exception of the Social Security Number Protection Policy stated above which applies to all Lilly operations, applies only to the operation of U.S. websites that directly link to this statement when you click on "privacy statement" in the website footer.

**Personal Information Collected by Lilly Online**

Through this website, you may be asked to voluntarily provide to us information that can identify or locate you, such as your name, address, telephone number, e-mail address, and other similar information ("Personal Information"). You may always refuse to provide Personal Information to us, but this may lead to our inability to provide you with certain information, products, or services.

If you do provide us with Personal Information, we may enhance or merge it with information about you obtained from third parties for the same purposes. By using the site and providing us with your Personal Information, you consent to our use of such information as described in this Privacy Statement

We may use your Personal Information:

  * To respond to your requests for information, products, services;
  * If you apply for a job via our career center, to consider you for employment;
  * If you register online, to administer your account;
  * To provide you with general health information (such as information on certain health conditions) as well as information about our products and services;
  * If you have a business or professional relationship with Lilly, we may use your Personal Information generally to develop our business relationship with you;
  * For legal compliance, such as adverse event reporting or to enforce our rights; and
  * For other everyday business purposes, such as website management, research and product development.

**Other Information Collected by Lilly Online**

We may also collect information that does not identify you ("Other Information"), such as the date and time of website session, movements across our website, and information about your browser, We do not tie Other Information to Personal Information. This Other Information may be used and stored by Lilly or its agents. Other Information we collect may include your IP Address (a number used to identify your computer on the Internet) and other information gathered through our weblogs, cookies or by other means (see below). We use Other Information to administer and update our website and for other everyday business purposes. Lilly reserves the right to maintain, update, disclose or otherwise use Other Information, without limitation.

This site may use a technology known as web beacons — sometimes called single-pixel gifs — that allow this site to collect web log information. A web beacon is a graphic on a web page or in an e-mail message designed to track pages viewed or messages opened. Web log information is gathered when you visit one of our websites by the computer that hosts our website (called a "webserver"). The webserver automatically recognizes some non-personal information, such as the date and time you visited our site, the pages you visited, the website you came from, the type of browser you are using (e.g., Internet Explorer), the type of operating system you are using (e.g., Windows 2000), and the domain name and address of your Internet service provider (e.g., AOL). We may also include web beacons in promotional e-mail messages in order to determine whether messages have been opened.

This website may use a technology called a "cookie". A cookie is a piece of information that our webserver sends to your computer (actually to your browser file) when you access a website. Then when you come back our site will detect whether you have one of our cookies on your computer. Our cookies help provide additional functionality to the site and help us analyze site usage more accurately. For instance, our site may set a cookie on your browser that keeps you from needing to remember and then enter a password more than once during a visit to the site. With most Internet browsers or other software, you can erase cookies from your computer hard drive, block all cookies or receive a warning before a cookie is stored. Please refer to your browser instructions to learn more about these functions. If you reject cookies, functionality of the site may be limited, and you may not be able to take advantage of many of the site's features.

This website collects and uses Internet Protocol (IP) Addresses. An IP Address is a number assigned to your computer by your Internet service provider so you can access the Internet. Generally, an IP address changes each time you connect to the Internet (it is a "dynamic" address). Note, however, that if you have a broadband connection, depending on your individual circumstance, it is possible that your IP Address that we collect, or even perhaps a cookie we use, may contain information that could be deemed identifiable. This is because with some broadband connections your IP Address doesn't change (it is "static") and could be associated with your personal computer. We use your IP address to report aggregate information on use and to help improve the website.

**Information Disclosures and Sharing**

Except as provided below, Lilly will not share your Personal Information with third parties unless you have consented to the disclosure.

We may share your Personal Information with our agents, contractors or partners in connection with services that these individuals or entities perform for, or with, Lilly, such as sending email messages, managing data, hosting our databases, providing data processing services or providing customer service. These agents, contractors or partners are restricted from using this data in any way other than to provide services for

Lilly, or services for the collaboration in which they and Lilly are engaged (for example, some of our products are developed and marketed through joint agreements with other companies).

Lilly will share Personal Information to respond to duly authorized subpoenas or information requests of governmental authorities, to provide Internet security or where required by law. In exceptionally rare circumstances where national, state or company security is at issue, Lilly reserves the right to share our entire database of visitors and customers with appropriate governmental authorities.

We may also provide Personal Information and Other Information to a third party in connection with the sale, assignment, or other transfer of the business of this website to which the information relates, in which case we will require any such buyer to agree to treat Personal Information in accordance with this Privacy Statement.

**Your Choices**

Lilly will respect your marketing and communications preferences. You can opt-out of receiving commercial emails from us at any time by following the opt-out instructions in our commercial emails. You can also request removal from all our contact lists, by writing to us at the following address:

Eli Lilly and Company  
P.O. Box 6245  
Indianapolis, IN 46206-6245

Or call Lilly toll-free at 1-800-LillyRx (1-800-545-5979).

Please be sure to include your email address if you are writing to unsubscribe. Also, please note that you may continue to receive materials while we are updating our lists.

**Children’s Information**

This site is not intended for or designed to attract individuals under the age of 18. We do not knowingly collect Personal Information from any person under the age of 18.

**Information Security**

Areas of this website that collect Personal Information you voluntarily provide to us use reasonable security protections designed to protect this information.

**Links to Third Party Websites**

As a convenience to our visitors, this Website currently contains links to a number of sites owned and operated by third parties that we believe may offer useful information. The policies and procedures we describe here do not apply to those sites. Lilly is not responsible for the collection or use of Personal Information or Other Information at any third party sites. Therefore, Lilly disclaims any liability for any third party's use of Personal Information or Other Information obtained through using the third party web site. We suggest contacting those sites directly for information on their privacy, security, data collection, and distribution policies.

**Changes to Our Privacy Practices**

We may update this Privacy Statement from time to time. When we do update it, for your convenience, we will make the updated statement available on this page. We will always handle your Personal Information in accordance with the Privacy Statement in effect at the time it was collected. We will not make any materially different use or new disclosure of your Personal Information unless we notify you and give you an opportunity to object.

**For More Information**

If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Statement, please contact us by writing to:

Eli Lilly and Company  
P.O. Box 6245  
Indianapolis, IN 46206-6245

Or calling Lilly toll-free at 1-800-LillyRx (1-800-545-5979).

**Resolving Your Privacy Concerns**

If, after attempting to address a privacy question or concern with Lilly directly by contacting us using the contact information listed above, you still have a specific privacy concern that has not been resolved, you may choose mediation of that concern by the neutral third party, American Arbitration Association. Submit your unresolved privacy concern to the American Arbitration Association for resolution.

American Arbitration Association

Case Filing Services  
877.495.4185: Toll free  
877.304.8457: Fax  

Last Updated: January 26, 2016
